我们已经讨论过像素速度-或图像平面速度-是如何相关的
We have already discussed how the pixel velocity — or the image plane velocity — is related
通过图像雅可比矩阵得到相机速度。但是，这些数量都是相互关联的。
to the camera velocity by the image Jacobian matrix. But, these quantities are all interrelated.
如果我们知道一些，我们可以使用该信息来估计其他人。雅可比矩阵取决于
If we know some, we can use that information to estimate others. The Jacobian matrix depends
在一个恒定的参数上非常清楚：f-hat-与焦距有关;这取决于
very clearly on a constant parameter: f-hat — related to the focal length; it depends
在点u和v的图像平面坐标上;它还取决于的深度
on image plane coordinate of a point u and v; and it also depends on the depth of the
point-3D空间中点的Z坐标。值得注意的是，有趣的是
point — the Z coordinate of the point in 3D space. It is interesting to note that the
点的深度-资本Z仅出现在图像雅可比矩阵的前三列中。
depth of the point — Capital Z occurs only in the first three columns of the image Jacobian matrix.
假设我们想利用这种相互关系来估计到点的距离。
Let's say we want to use this interrelationship to estimate the distance to a point.
如果我们观察一系列图像中的一个点，我们就可以计算出它的速度
If we look at a point across a sequence of images we can compute its velocity in the
图像平面。我们知道图像平面上的点的坐标，我们可以测量
image plane. We know the coordinate of the point on the image plane, and we can measure
使用像惯性测量单元这样的相机速度，可以说明
the camera velocity using something like an inertial measurement unit, which would tell
我们的旋转速度，也给我们速度。所以，如果我们知道这三个
us the rotational velocities and also give us the velocity. So if we know these three
事情然后，解决到点的距离是相当直接的。
things then it is reasonably straightforward to solve for the distance to the point.
现在考虑我们想要估计相机速度的问题。
Consider now the problem where we want to estimate the speed of the camera.
因此，我们可以通过查看场景中的某些点来再次测量像素速度
So we can again measure the pixel velocity by looking at some points in a scene across
一系列图像。我们知道图像中某点的u和v坐标。在这
a sequence of images. We know the u and v coordinate of a point in the image. In this
我们需要确定到点的距离，我们可以使用类似立体声的东西
case we need to determine the distance to the point and we can use something like stereo
愿意告诉我们一个物体远离相机的距离。一旦我们有这三个
vision to tell us how far an object is away from the camera. Once we have these three
然后我们可以解决相机速度的信息。和像这样的技术
pieces of information then we can solve for the camera velocity. And a technique like
这被称为视觉测距。里程表是移动机器人上的设备
this is referred to as visual odometry. An odometer is a device on a mobile robot that
计算车轮的旋转以确定您移动的距离。视觉
counts the rotation of the wheels to determine how far it is that you have moved. Visual
odometry提供相同的信息，但实际上并不需要车轮和里程表。
odometry provides the same information, but doesn't actually require a wheel and an odometer.
它通过观察世界如何流过相机来估计这一点。
It estimates this by observing how the world is flowing past the camera.
让我们考虑一个视觉测距的简单例子。
Let's consider a simple example of visual odometry.
这是我们以前见过的表达，但我突出了两个子矩阵;他们
This is an expression that we have seen before, but I have highlighted two sub-matrices; they
都是1x3子矩阵。我将把它们中的一个表示为Jsubu，其中一个表示为Jsub
are both 1x3 sub-matrices. I am going to denote one of them J sub u and one of them as J sub
v。我们假设机器人在X，Y平面上移动，并且世界是一个常数
v. We assume that the robot is moving in the X,Y plane and that the world is a constant
离机器人的距离。
distance away from the robot.
我们谈到过光流。在特定的像素坐标处，我们可以确定它的速度
We've talked about optical flow. At a particular pixel coordinate we can determine it’s velocity
在图像平面中，它为我们提供了信息u-dot和v-dot。我们可以使用惯性测量
in the image plane and that gives us the information u-dot and v-dot. We can use an inertial measurement
单元。我们可以使用这个特定传感器测量的瞬时角速度
unit. We can use the instantaneous angular velocity measured by this particular sensor
我们可以将其替换为元素omega-X的空间速度向量，
and we can substitute that into the spatial velocity vector for the elements omega-X,
omega-Y和omega-Z。因为机器人相对于恒定的距离移动
omega-Y, and omega-Z. Because the robot is moving at a constant distance with respect
对于世界，Z是已知的，Z是常数，所以我们可以说vZ是近似的
to the world then Z is known, and Z is constant, so we can say that the vZ is approximately
等于零。雅可比图像中有一些元素并不特别
equal to zero. There are some elements in the image Jacobian that are not particularly
重大。它们的值接近零，所以作为一阶近似，我们可以
significant. Their value is close to zero, so as a first order approximation we can just
把它们留下来结果就是我们可以写一个简化的
leave them out. The result then is that we can write a simplified
根据vX和vY表示u-dot和v-dot，摄像机的速度
expression for u-dot and v-dot in terms of vX and vY, the velocity of the camera which
实际上是我们试图确定的信息，以及物距
is actually the information that we are trying to determine, as well as the object distance
-世界距离，雅可比图像的子矩阵和角速度
— the world distance, the sub-matrices of the image Jacobian, and the angular velocity
相机我们可以重新排列这个以获得表达式
of the camera. We can rearrange this to get expressions for
根据我们能够测量的各种数量，相机的速度。
the velocity of the camera in terms of various quantities that we are able to measure.
所以没有车轮，没有实际的编码器或里程表，我们可以估算
So without having a wheel and without having an actual encoder or an odometer we can estimate
当我们的飞机在空中移动时，它的速度。
the velocity of our aircraft, as it's moving through the air.
视觉里程表非常适合没有传统里程表的机器人。该
Visual odometry is really well suited to robots that don't have conventional odometers. The
传统的里程表要求你有一个轮子和某种计数器
conventional odometer requires that you have got a wheel and some kind of counter that
告诉你车轮转了多少次。如果它是飞行机器人或它是在水下
tells you how many times the wheel has turned. If it is a flying robot or if it is an underwater
机器人，然后它没有轮子，然后视觉里程计是一个非常有用的传感模式。
robot then it doesn't have wheels and then visual odometry is a really useful sensing modality.
所以在这里我们可以看到水下机器人。它正在使用其立体相机来维持
So here we can see the underwater robot. It is using its stereo cameras to maintain a
海床上空恒定的高度。它还计算光流。它正在结合
constant altitude above the seabed. It is also computing optical flow. And it is combining
具有来自立体视觉的高度信息，并结合使用
that with the height information that comes from the stereo vision, and combined with
来自车载陀螺仪的一些信息-它赋予它'角速率-以便
some information from onboard gyroscopes — which give it its' angular rate — in order to
确定它相对于海床的速度。例如，如果有海洋
determine its velocity with respect to the seabed. If, for example, there is an ocean
当前将机器人推向侧面，然后视觉测距会将其拾起。这里将
current pushing the robot sideways then the visual odometry will pick this up. There will
是速度的Y分量，然后机器人上的控制系统可以应用
be a Y component of velocity and then the control system onboard the robot can apply
适当的螺旋桨推力，以对抗。所以视觉测距法告诉机器人
appropriate propeller thrust in order to counter that. So visual odometry is telling the robot
它相对于海床的真实速度。
its true velocity with respect to the seabed.